<thing id="eqACBlut" name="Der Blutfahne" compset="Equipment" description="In the presence of the Blutfahne, all Persuasion attempts against members of the German military who have taken the oath to the Fuhrer gain a +2 bonus if carried out by a senior German officer, whereas all such attempts by an obvious enemy of the Reich suffer a -2 penalty. ">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACETSt" name="Elder Thing Staff" compset="Equipment" description="As soon as the staff is picked up, it inflicts a -1 penalty on all rolls to unshake upon the wielder; for every time the character says “yes”, the staff inflicts a further -1 penalty to unshake. On a suc- cessful Smarts check, the bearer will sense they are getting weaker the longer they are in the dream and can take appro- priate action. The only way this penalty can be reduced is with Natural Healing rolls (as detailed in the Savage Worlds core rulebook, Chapter 3: Game Rules). Once the Elder Thing Staff has reached 4 wounds it becomes fully awake and protects the bearer as described.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACMGCl" compset="Equipment" name="Mi-Go Cloak" description="This device meshes with the arm of the user, causing the wearer to be Shaken when removed. It makes the wearer invisible to other mi-gos, elder things, yithians, deep ones, insects from Shaggai, and serpent people but, for some reason, not humans. Other senses, such as touch and smell, are unaffected by the cloak. This effect lasts for 1d6 rounds, after which the device starts inflicting 1d4 damage every round the user wishes to stay invisible.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACMMTr" compset="Equipment" name="Mi-Go Matter Transplacer" description="This metallic 1ft-long rod covered in exposed metal wires must be clutched tightly around one end. The other end then projects a large force-like hand out to a distance of about 30-50ft (9-15m). The strength of the pressure applied to the rod allows a grasping action with the “hand”, ena- bling the user to pick up very large objects and move them around. In order to make the rod usable by a human, it must first be re-wired. Jury-rigged, the Matter Transplacer will then only work on a result of 1-4 on 1D6. However, even when configured correctly, it still requires consid- erable effort for a human to maintain the mental effort necessary to manipulate the “hand” and, as such, anyone attempting to use the Matter Transplacer loses 1D4 Hit Points for every 220lbs (100kg) moved per turn. Two successful Repair rolls are required to rewire the Transplacer. If a 5 or 6 is rolled when determining if the Transplacer is working, further use cannot be attempted until another successful Repair check has been achieved.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACPoLn" compset="Equipment" name="Pyramic of Leng" description="These jet-black pyramids, standing 6ft (1.8m) along each side and 5ft (1.5m) in height, originate from the obsidian bedrock of the Valley of the Black Sun (p.77). Engraved with complex geometric patterns and sigils that shift before the eye, the pyramids give the impression that their lines should not form a true pyramid, causing great discomfort to those attempting to decipher their carvings. The formulae for creating these edifices are given to Reinhardt Weissler by Nyarlathotep himself to assist in his quest to release the Black Sun from its prison within the Dreamlands. Their purpose is to break down the barriers between the worlds, with the ultimate aim of bringing the dreaming and waking worlds together. Due to its unnatural formation, a Pyramid of Leng can only be created in the Dreamlands. Black Sun has formed a number of these Pyramids and placed them within the grounds of Wewelsburg Castle to aid their sorcerers in their work, and in preparation for the eventual harmonisation of the site with its dreaming duplicate (p.84). The Pyramids are extremely heavy and impervious to most damage, with only High Explosives having enough destructive power to wipe them out. Black Sun is very pro- tective of these artefacts due to the great effort required to move them from the Dreamlands into the waking world. Characters must make a Nausea (-1) check when trying to read the runes and patterns carved upon a Pyramid of Leng or suffer the relevant effects. The necessary spell for the creation of a Pyramid carries a Casting Modifier of -10 and must be cast whilst engraving takes place and the correct ritual chants recited. Once activated and brought into the waking world, a Pyramid halves the Casting Modifier of any spell cast within 100ft (30m) of the structure.">
 	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACShaS" name="Shaggai Sword" compset="Equipment" description="This cruel sword inflicts pain on the user but doubly so on its target. The sword administers 1D6/1d6 Hit Points of damage to the holder and double the result of that roll to the target on a successful hit.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACTotR" name="Totenkopfringe" compset="Equipment" description="Officially named SS-Ehrenringe (“SS Honour Rings”), but better known as Totenkopfringe (“Skull Rings”) for their macabre design, these silver rings are individually inscribed for each wearer. Designed by Karl Maria Wiligut, although frequently worn as a symbol of rank and pride, their original purpose is to prevent those passing through the Wewelsburg gate to the Dreamlands from suffering the crippling phys- ical sickness that afflicts most travellers. They also have the benefit of providing protection against die Gefallenen, which are rendered blind to the wearer’s presence, ensuring Black Sun forces are not set upon by their own undead creations. In addition, the rings shield their wearers from the bloodborn (p.232). The rings also serve a secret purpose added by Weissler and known only to his Priors and Canons. When the cor- rect incantation (Leech Essence/leech essence) is invoked, a sorcerer can drain any individual wearing an SS-Ehrenring within his line of sight (see p.213 for further details). Unwit- tingly, the SS have become a vast magical reserve for Black Sun’s ultimate rites. All members of Black Sun are presented with their rings upon initiation, while SS recipients are given theirs after three years of loyal service. Closely guarded, every effort is made to ensure the rings of fallen SS members are returned to Wewelsburg, though in the carnage of battle a few may be lost.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACTcry" name="Tainted Crystal of the Elder Things" compset="Equipment" description="Its purpose bent to an alien will, whilst it looks like an ancient storage device, the Tainted Crystal is, in fact, designed to temporarily drain a person's ability to cast Mythos magic, draining 1 die of the Knowledge (Mythos) skill level per round; once this has been depleted, or if a character is without Knowledge (Mythos), the crystal drains the target’s life force, causing a level of Fatigue per round until the person or creature is knocked unconscious, or the crystal is shattered by something (Object Toughness 8). The subject is completely unable to act whilst the crystal is draining them. If the person or crystal is forci- bly removed, the person suffers Horror (+1) per round from terrible hallucinations until they are at least 100ft (30m) away from the crystal. The Knowledge (Mythos) skill slowly returns at one die per hour, as does the Fatigue, so an investigator who has a Knowledge (Mythos) of d6 will have it fully restored in two hours if it had all been drained away.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="Misc"/>
</thing>

<thing id="eqACYMS" name="Yithian Mind Stamp" compset="Equipment" description="This device looks like a large, shaped pebble with various raised ridges on each side. Once gripped in the palm of the hand the Mind Stamp turns itself on. It has been pre-loaded with the desires, thoughts, and knowledge of three human minds from many centuries ago. A random mind will take over the holder of the Mind Stamp for 1D6 rounds, and the bearer’s mind can only be freed from the temporary imprisonment by forcible removal of the pebble from his hand. An affected person will resist efforts to remove the pebble, and this is likely to cause injury to his hand whilst doing so. The pre-loaded minds are likely to be insane from hundreds or thousands of years of being trapped inside the Mind Stamp, but they are still capable of using the holder’s speech to communicate. It is possible that the imprisoned consciousnesses know something very relevant to the investigators’ current predicament, and if they can be calmed down or reasoned with, they can reveal useful information. Any attempts to remove the Mind Stamp from a person’s hand causes 2d4 damage as a result of their struggle to maintain a grip on it.">
	<usesource source="ACKG"/>
	<tag group="GearType" tag="misc"/>
</thing>